Inventory of the Jerdone Family Papers 1753-1890, 1771-1845
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Correspondence, 1753-1890. (Box 1-10)
  - Letters, 1840-1849., 147 items. (Box-folder 9:2-8)
    - Letters, 1845., 21 items. (Box-folder 9:6)
      - John Jerdone, Spotsylvania County, [Virginia] to his brother, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling," [Charles City County], Virginia, 6 March 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Refers to trip from Richmond on train; reports weather and crop; refers to discovery of lice on horses; describes treatment for delousing; other family news.
      - Eliza [Merrill?], Oswego, New York to Anna E. V. Burfitt, Troy, New York, 18 March 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Praises Anna E. V. Burfitt as a good friend; discusses her difficulty in transition to Oswego; requests her [Anna E. V. Burfitt] to visit; complains of Methodist preachers not being all the same; requests advice on books to read.
      - Louise [May], Middlebury, Vermont to Anna Burfitt, "Female Seminary," Troy, New York, 3 April 1845., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Advise on male interests; reports on local gossip; discusses desire to move to Virginia as teacher.
      - John Jerdone, Spotsylvania County, [Virginia] to his brother, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling," [Charles City County], Virginia, 4 April 1845., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Reports on children and health of family; relates progress of crops; refers to court case against Hart, Collins; other family news.
      - Richa[rd] Tucker, "Mount Sterling," Ch[arle]s City [County, Virginia] to William Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia. 13 May 1845., 1 page. L. (Possibly not in his hand.) (Box-folder 9:6)
        Report on crops; refers to fish caught; other news.
      - Richa[rd] Tucker, Ch[arle]s City County, [Virginia] to William Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia 21 May 1845., 2 pages. L. (Possibly not in his hand.) (Box-folder 9:6)
        Reports on progress of crops and weather; refers to shearing sheep, hatching of turkeys and other references to livestock; refers to selection of school for Maria; other news.
      - George Pottie, Pottiesville, [Virginia] to his cousin, William Jerdone, Louisa [County], Virginia, 5 June 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Reports can give bond "with everything requisite to your safety".
      - Maria C. Jerdone, n.p. to her father, William Jerdone, Charles City [County, Virginia], 18 June 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Writes from school; expresses happiness and comfort; refers to sores almost healed; reports visit to St. James's Church and seeing organ; looks forward to his visit; refers to General Jackson's death; other family news.
      - Jno. Jerdone, Spotsylvania County, [Virginia] to his brother, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling", [Charles City County], Virginia, 5 July 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Discusses Maria's entrance in school; refers to progress of crops and sale of tobacco; refers to "railroad meeting" and decision of a 3% dividend to be paid; other family news.
      - L. Wortham and M. Gruster, Richmond, [Virginia] to William Jerdone, "Frederick Hall", Louisa County, Virginia, 4 August 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Reports sale of corn; states prices of wheat.
      - Jno. Jerdone, Spotsylvania County, [Virginia] to his brother, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling", [Charles City County], Virginia, 27 October 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Refers to Maria at school; refers to intention to sell "a parcel of Negroes" as he [John Jerdone] is "entirely overstocked with them"; reports on weather, crops and prices; other family news.
      - Maria C. Jerdone, Richmond, [Virginia] to her father, William Jerdone, ["Mount Sterling", Charles City County, Virginia], 3 November 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Reports visit by Mary and her parents; refers to case of scarlet fever; reports visit to "caravan" to see wild animals; other family news.
        Includes N by [?] Mead to William Jerdone, reporting case of fever is better; Maria is well and a good scholar.
      - Charles S. Jones, Near Louisa Co[urt] House to John Jerdone, [Spotsylvania County, Virginia], 17 November 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Request for payment of bill for bacon, etc. so he can pay his taxes.
      - F[rancis] Jerdone, Bloomsbury, [Virginia] to his brother, William Jerdone, Spotsylvania County, Virginia, 26 December 1845., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:6)
        Reports filling of ice house; discusses crops and prices; has received letter from Chapman Johnson referring to judgment in his case against Allison and Watt; other family news.
    - Letters, 1846., 18 items. (Box-folder 9:7)
      - L[ouise] [May?], "Summer Hill", Han[ove]r County, [Virginia] to Anna Burfitt, Pottiesville, Louisa County, Virginia, 9 March 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Expresses sympathy to Anna for an unknown occurrence; reports latest letter from Eliza Merrill and expresses sympathy for the loss of her brother; remarks on dearness of Anna as a friend; reports on her own brother, Dan.
      - Fra[nci]s Jerdone, Bloomsbury, Orange County, [Virginia] to his brother, William Jerdone, New Kent C[ourt] H[ouse], Virginia, 13 March 1846., 3 pages. Cy of ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Describes recent snowstorm and general weather; refers to a scarcity of food for [live]stock; death of slave Rosetta; refers to crops and large number of crows; other family news.
      - Jno. G. B. Coleman, "Coleman's Mills", Louisa County, [Virginia] to William Jerdone, New Kent C[our]t Ho[use], Virginia, 17 March 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Complains of a lack of anyone in his employment in the tanyard or shoe shop whom he can trust; refers to crops and prices; bad snowstorm; reports sale of slaves; other family news.
      - Louise [May?], "Summer Hill", [Hanover County, Virginia] to Anna Burfitt, Pottiesville, Louisa County, [Virginia], 25 March 1846., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Relates school children's interest in her [Anna Burfitt]; anticipates Mr. Coleman's visit; refers to other social incidents.
      - Jno. Jerdone, Spotsylvania County, [Virginia] to his brother, William Jerdone, Powhatan House, Richmond, Virginia, 12 April 1846., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Refers to Maria's case of measles; reports children Willie O. and Leonora are attending school; refers to Uncle Toby's school being full; other family news.
      - Jno. G. B. Coleman, "Mount Sterling Estate", Charles City [County, Virginia] to his niece, Maria Coleman Jerdone, Spotsylvania County, Virginia, 15 May 1846., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Refers to "happiness" in "mutually edifying" correspondence; reports cats trick of climbing into pigeon house and killing pigeons; refers to new born livestock; other family news.
      - Jno. Jerdone, Spotsylvania County, [Virginia] to his brother, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling", [Charles City County], Virginia, 22 May 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Reports on development of crops; saving of 100 sheep from drowning by hands swimming in and bringing them out one at a time; refers to group of men sentenced to the penitentiary for unspecified crimes; refers to jailing of 8 negroes for "insurrectionary proceedings"; "I have understood that it was a very extensive plot... many whites it is supposed concerned in the business..."; other family news.
      - E[liza?] [Merrill?], Chicago, [Illinois] to Anna [Burfitt], n.p., 1 June 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Explains delay in answer of letter; consoles her [Anna Burfitt] on loss of her sister; brother's account of Mexican War; relates other family feeling and social incidents.
      - Maria C[oleman] Jerdone, Richmond, [Virginia] to her father, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling", [Charles City County, Virginia], 10 June 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Reports attending church twice previous days; refers to expectation of frocks; reports attending one dancing lesson; other family news.
      - Louise [May?], n.p. to Anna [Burfitt], n.p., 19 July 1846. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Describes the scene she is in as she writes letter; refers to Mr. Jerdone visiting her [Anna Burfitt]; relates Plans to meet her in Richmond; other social news.
      - Louise [May?], Fairfield, Goochland [County, Virginia] to Anna Burfitt, Pottiesville, Louisa County, Virginia, 27 July 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Describes trip to Richmond and misfortune of losing her trunk; expresses disappointment in not visiting Louisa County; other social news.
      - William Jerdone, Richmond, [Virginia] to his brother, Francis Jerdone, Bloomsbury, Orange [County], Virginia, 27 August 1846., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Reports plans to visit soon; refers to health of family; reports C. G. Coleman's loss of two slaves; other family news.
      - [Louise?], "Summer Hill," [Hanover County, Virginia] to Anna [Burfitt], n.p., 23 October 1846., 4 page. AL. Incomplete. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Remarks upon "drudgery of teaching"; advises Anna Burfitt on how to schedule her classes and gives her schedule; her failed attempts to make friends in the neighborhood; has therefore "relapsed into the same cold calculating Yankee;" reports on two new teachers; other social news.
      - Louise [?], ["Summer Hill"] to [Anna Burfitt], n.p., 26 October 1846., 4 pages. ALS. Incomplete. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Speculates on recent notice of sale by Henry Birge and John Wainwright; discusses Mr. Jerdone's intentions; expresses concern over the difference in ages; refers to Mr. Boxley's affections for her [Anna Burfitt]; other social news.
      - Maria Jerdone, "Jerdone Castle", [Louisa County, Virginia] to her father, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling", [Charles City County], Virginia, 28 October [18]46., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Reports satisfaction with her new frocks; thanks him for the package; accepts hint to darn her stockings.
      - Jno. Jerd[one], Spotsylvania County, [Virginia] to his brother, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling", [Charles City County], Virginia, 2 November 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Refers to weather and effect on crops; comments on Miss Burfitt as Maria's teacher; refers to hogs and prices for crops; other family news.
      - Maria C[oleman] Jerdone, "Jerdone Castle", [Louisa County, Virginia] to her father, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling", [Charles City County], Virginia, 11 December [18]46., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Reports painting of pigeon house; lists subjects she is studying; reports recent deaths; other family news.
      - Louise [May?], "Summer Hill," [Virginia] to Anna Burfitt, Pottiesville, Louisa County, Virginia, 11 December 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:7)
        Describes her recent illness of typhus fever and resulting weakness; advises her [Anna Burfitt] on courtship of Mr. Jerdone; other social news.
    - Letters, 1847., 10 items. (Box-folder 9:8)
      - [Guten & Guten?], n.p. to William Jerdone, New Kent [County, Virginia], 20 January 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Discusses buying price of his [William Jerdone] corn.
      - [Guten & Guten?], Richmond, [Virginia] to William Jerdone, New Kent [County], Virginia, 24 January 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Settles buying price for his [William Jerdone] corn.
      - [Guten & Guten?], [Richmond, Virginia] to William Jerdone, New Kent C[our]t House, [Virginia], 1 February 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Refers to engagement of Capt. Fletcher; intends to ship plaster by first vessel.
      - Maria Coleman Jerdone, n.p. to her father, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling", [Charles City County, Virginia], 28 February 1847., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Reports measles cases; reports receipt of gifts and food sent; refers to Miss Burfitt; other family news; marriage of Lafayette Riordon to Mary Boxley.
      - [Guten & Guten?], [Richmond, Virginia] to William Jerdone, New Kent [County, Virginia], 3 March 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Reports arrival of vessel and loading of articles; reports no herrings available in New Kent.
      - John P. Pivir, n.p. to William Jerdone, "Providence Forge", [New Kent County, Virginia], 22 March 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Requests good brandy for his sick father.
      - [Louise May], "Summer Hill", to Anna [Burfitt], n.p., 24 April 1847., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Refers to her recent depression; refers to Mr. Jerdone and speculates on future; reports on measles outbreak and children's reaction to possibility of contracting disease; refers to receipt of a manuscript copy of The Raven by Edgar Allan Poe sent from Maine; other social news.
      - Maria C[oleman] Jerdone, "Jerdone Castle", [Louisa County, Virginia] to her father, William Jerdone, "Mount Sterling", [Charles City County, Virginia], 8 June [18]47., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Discusses Miss Burfitt's opinion on her new bonnet; refers to classes and instruction; other family news.
      - William [?], Concord Academy to his uncle, William Jerdone, Charles City [County], Virginia, 17 June 1847., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Refers to his [William Jerdone] new house; discusses things he'd like to do when he comes home from school; other family news.
      - William Jerdone, Charles City [County, Virginia] to David S. Crump, n.p., 2 November 1847., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
        Discusses settlement for timber cut for William Jerdone by David Crump's men.
        Includes ANS marking receipt of payment.
    - Louise [May], "Summer Hill" to [Anna Burfitt], n.p., 8 April 1848., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Refers to her illness; discusses plans to visit her [Anna Burfitt]; refers to other social incidents.
    - [John Jerdone?], St. Charles Hotel, City of New Orleans, Louisiana to his brother [William Jerdone], 16 May 1848., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Describes his travels from Kentucky to New Orleans, towns and country he traveled through in Mississippi and some of the sights he saw.
    - J[ohn] J[erdone], Henderson, Kentucky to his brother, William Jerdone, "Mt. Sterling", [Charles City County], Virginia, 1 June 1848., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Reports health of family; refers to his [William Jerdone] business and running plantation; describes visit to New Orleans and southern states; describes 'Mississippi River and great amount of activity and trade taking place; reports land prices for land along Mississippi; describes amount of crops could be grown on land he is looking into; refers to people he has met who are old acquaintances; other family news.
    - Louise [May], "Summer Hill", [Virginia] to Anna [Burfitt] Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia, July 1848., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Refers to her trip North for the summer; expresses disappointment that she [Anna Burfitt Jerdone] won't be going; refers to travel plans and hopes to see her in Richmond; other family news.
      Also includes ANS from Louise [?] to Anna [Burfitt] Jerdone, dated 25 July [1848] concerning Dr. B.'s illness and delay in trip.
    - Louise [May], Middlebury, [Vermont] to Anna [Burfitt] Jerdone, n.p., 6 March 1849., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Refers to delinquency in letters; refers to her [Anna Burfitt Jerdone] motherhood; reports on winter in the North; refers to sleigh-riding and snowball throwing; other news.
    - Louise [May], Middlebury, [Vermont] to Anna [Burfitt] Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 11 August 1849., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Expresses deep emotion for friendship with her [Anna Burfitt Jerdone]; inquires after son, William; refers to offer of appointment in Shepherdstown, Virginia; other news.
    - Louise [May], Shepherdstown, [Virginia] to Anna [Burfitt] Jerdone, n.p., November 1849., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Expresses unhappiness at her new position; discusses plans to take other position with Mr. Winston; describes schoolroom and dormitory; other news.
  - Letters, 1850-1859., 5 items. (Box-folder 9:8-9)
    - Louise [May], Shepherdstown, [Virginia] to Anna [Burfitt] Jerdone, [Charles City County], Virginia, 18 July 1850., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Reports travel northward.
    - Louise May, Middlebury, [Vermont] to [Anna Burfitt Jerdone], n.p., 11 September 1850., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Reports on commencement activities; requests a letter soon; reports on old acquaintances from school; other news.
    - Poem or hymn by John Jerdone entitled The Cross about Christ's death and saving of mankind, 6 September 1853. (Box-folder 9:9)
    - NS by William H. Clapton et al., managers inviting [?] to a party at the Charles City County, [Virginia] Courthouse, 9 February [18]55. (Box-folder 9:)
    - J. B. Lowrie, Powhatan, [Virginia] to William Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 20 October 1855., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Inquires after borrowing $500 for an unspecified reason.
  - Letters, 1860-1869., 11 items. (Box-folder 9:9)
    - Andrew N. Gill, Jamestown Island, [Virginia] to [William] Jerdone, Wilcox's Wharf, Charles City County, Virginia, 30 July 1861., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Reports bacon loaded on ship to Mr. J.; heard today we have orders to move to Mulberry Island tomorrow morning; will send more if they don't leave; sends $10 Co wife; other references to the goods.
    - Blair & Chamberlayne, Richmond, [Virginia] to William Jerdone, n.p., 29 August [18]61., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Reports goods sent; explains smaller supply of sugar because of scarcity of all goods.
    - Report of Nathaniel Holman concerning three tracks of land in Monongalu County, Virginia [West Virginia] owned by William Holt and his sons, 16 September 1862., 3 pages. D. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Includes his instructions from William DuVal acting for Francis Jerdone. (1756-1841.)
    - W[illia]m Jerdone, Ch[arle]s City [County, Virginia] to [his brother, Francis Jerdone, "Bloomsbury", Orange County, Virginia], 29 April 1863., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Describes movements of both Confederate and Union troops on and about his plantation after the Confederate retreat from Yorktown the year before; describes battles of Civil War nearby including battle, 30 June [1862], at his house and damage done; and use of his house in August 1862 as Union Army headquarters; other family news.
    - W. H. Pleasants, Richmond, [Virginia] to William Jerdone, n.p., 13 November 1863., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Refers to goods ordered; reports efforts to settle accounts; refers to attempts to find someone [?] in prison.
    - Blair & Chamberlayne, [Richmond, Virginia] to William Jerdone, n.p., [April 1864]., 1 page. LS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      "The first of April being an Era in our resolution we are making efforts to start fresh from that time;" remit money owed; bears account, 1863-1864, of William Jerdone.
    - S. B. Smith, Richmond, Virginia to Mrs. Anna B[urfitt] Jerdone, n.p., 7 November 1866., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Reports entering money into accounts; advises her to "be cautious and collect up close and also to look close after your affairs."
    - Blair & Chamberlayne, Richmond, [Virginia] to Mrs. William Jerdone [Anna (Burfitt) Jerdone], 23 July 1867., 1 page. LS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Blair having failed, he is pressed for money; requests she pay money owed.
      Includes invoice, 1861-1863, converted from Confederate funds to U.S. funds.
    - John Blair, Richmond, [Virginia] to Mrs. [Anna Burfitt] Jerdone, n. p., 9 August 1867., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Explains no copy of bill to show how account was come to; describes method of settling accounts of Confederate times into current currency; other business news.
    - John Blair, Richmond, [Virginia] to Mrs. [Anna Burfitt] Jerdone, n.p., 19 September 1868., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Requests settlement of claim made by Blair and Chamberlayne.
    - John Blair, Richmond, [Virginia] to Mrs. [Anna Burfitt] Jerdone, n.p., 7 August 1869., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Expects claim by Blair & Chamberlayne to be settled now that wheat is in.
  - Letters, 1870-1890., 9 items. (Box-folder 9:9)
    - John Blair, Savannah, Georgia to Mrs. [Anna Burfitt] Jerdone, n.p., 25 September 1871., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Requests payment of claim; asks three neighbors to determine value of articles now in Richmond and settlement will be fed on that.
    - W. M. Jerdone, Galveston, Texas to his mother, [Anna Burfitt Jerdone], n.p., 10 August 1874., 10 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Reports receipt of gifts; describes daily newspaper; gives long and detailed description of court proceedings he was involved in.
    - W. M. Jerdone, Galveston, Texas to his mother, [Anna Burfitt Jerdone], n.p., 20 May 1876., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Inquires after papers sent; describes state fair and military men he met; describes Texas' position politically toward reconstruction.
    - Anna [Burfitt Jerdone], Retreat, Richmond, [Virginia] to her children, n.p., 7 December 1878., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Describes planned treatment of tumor; describes stay at retreat to sick hospital; kindness of Dr. [?] McGuire; other family news.
    - A. L. Shepherd, Richmond, Virginia to Frank [Jerdone], n.p., 19 December 1878., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Reports mother's [Anna Burfitt Jerdone] death; describes plan to move body home.
    - Jno. Lamb, "Green Yard," to Frank Jerdone, [Jr.], "Mt. Sterling," [Virginia], [19-20 December 1878]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Expresses sympathy for mother's [Anna Burfitt Jerdone] death; suggests transportation he has available for the family.
    - A. Wade, n.p. to Frank [?], n.p., 20 December 1878., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Expresses sympathy for their "affliction".
    - A. L. Shepherd & Co., [Richmond, Virginia] to Frank [Jerdone?], n.p., 24 December [18]78., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Reports sales of goods and sends goods ordered; advises against allowing "cargo to pass into the hands of strangers"; other business news.
    - W[illiam] M. Jerdone, Galveston, Texas to his aunt, [?], 26 September 1890., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 9:9)
      Expresses dissatisfaction with people in general and loneliness; refers to severe weather in Virginia; notes little severe weather in Texas and Galveston recently; other family news.
  - Letters, n.d., 40 items. (Box-folder 10:1-2)
    - Helen Maxwell Anderson, Williamsburg, [Virginia] to [Uncle] Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, n.d., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:1)
      Reports visit of cousins John and William; mother's health precarious; will try to convince her to visit her friends in the "upper country" this summer; hopes his family will visit.
    - E. Berkeley, n.p. to William Jerdone, Louisa [County], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 10:1)
      Has drawn against his account; wishes to have Mr. Coleman paid for the pork; consoles him in his bereavement.
    - W. Browne, n.p. to [?] Jerdone, Raleigh [Tavern, Williamsburg, Virginia], n.d., 1 page. AL. (Box-folder 10:1)
      Requests Jerdone to delay trip until the morning as the man "who has the fund out of which he is to pay Mr. Jerdone has not yet reached town"; does not wish Mr. Jerdone to leave town without his money.
    - William Coleman, n.p. to [uncle] William Jerdone, Pottiesville, Louisa County, Virginia, n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 10:1)